"use strict";(self.webpackChunksharek_dev=self.webpackChunksharek_dev||[]).push([[4700],{5788:(e,a,t)=>{t.d(a,{Iu:()=>g,yg:()=>N});var n=t(1504);function r(e,a,t){return a in e?Object.defineProperty(e,a,{value:t,enumerable:!0,configurable:!0,writable:!0}):e[a]=t,e}function p(e,a){var t=Object.keys(e);if(Object.getOwnPropertySymbols){var n=Object.getOwnPropertySymbols(e);a&&(n=n.filter((function(a){return Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptor(e,a).enumerable}))),t.push.apply(t,n)}return t}function i(e){for(var a=1;a<arguments.length;a++){var t=null!=arguments[a]?arguments[a]:{};a%2?p(Object(t),!0).forEach((function(a){r(e,a,t[a])})):Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptors?Object.defineProperties(e,Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptors(t)):p(Object(t)).forEach((function(a){Object.defineProperty(e,a,Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptor(t,a))}))}return e}function o(e,a){if(null==e)return{};var t,n,r=function(e,a){if(null==e)return{};var t,n,r={},p=Object.keys(e);for(n=0;n<p.length;n++)t=p[n],a.indexOf(t)>=0||(r[t]=e[t]);return r}(e,a);if(Object.getOwnPropertySymbols){var p=Object.getOwnPropertySymbols(e);for(n=0;n<p.length;n++)t=p[n],a.indexOf(t)>=0||Object.prototype.propertyIsEnumerable.call(e,t)&&(r[t]=e[t])}return r}var s=n.createContext({}),l=function(e){var a=n.useContext(s),t=a;return e&&(t="function"==typeof e?e(a):i(i({},a),e)),t},g=function(e){var a=l(e.components);return n.createElement(s.Provider,{value:a},e.children)},m="mdxType",y={inlineCode:"code",wrapper:function(e){var a=e.children;return n.createElement(n.Fragment,{},a)}},c=n.forwardRef((function(e,a){var t=e.components,r=e.mdxType,p=e.originalType,s=e.parentName,g=o(e,["components","mdxType","originalType","parentName"]),m=l(t),c=r,N=m["".concat(s,".").concat(c)]||m[c]||y[c]||p;return t?n.createElement(N,i(i({ref:a},g),{},{components:t})):n.createElement(N,i({ref:a},g))}));function N(e,a){var t=arguments,r=a&&a.mdxType;if("string"==typeof e||r){var p=t.length,i=new Array(p);i[0]=c;var o={};for(var s in a)hasOwnProperty.call(a,s)&&(o[s]=a[s]);o.originalType=e,o[m]="string"==typeof e?e:r,i[1]=o;for(var l=2;l<p;l++)i[l]=t[l];return n.createElement.apply(null,i)}return n.createElement.apply(null,t)}c.displayName="MDXCreateElement"},6332:(e,a,t)=>{t.r(a),t.d(a,{assets:()=>s,contentTitle:()=>i,default:()=>y,frontMatter:()=>p,metadata:()=>o,toc:()=>l});var n=t(5072),r=(t(1504),t(5788));const p={title:"Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark Exam questions"},i=void 0,o={unversionedId:"spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",id:"spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",title:"Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark Exam questions",description:"Here are 30 example questions for the Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark certification exam, along with their answers:",source:"@site/sections/data_processing/spark/06-articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam.md",sourceDirName:"spark/06-articles",slug:"/spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",permalink:"/data_processing/spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",draft:!1,tags:[],version:"current",frontMatter:{title:"Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark Exam questions"},sidebar:"docs",previous:{title:"Create a Spark plugin",permalink:"/data_processing/spark/customization/create-plugin"},next:{title:"Spark meets Go Lang",permalink:"/data_processing/spark/articles/spark-meets-go"}},s={},l=[],g={toc:l},m="wrapper";function y(e){let{components:a,...t}=e;return(0,r.yg)(m,(0,n.c)({},g,t,{components:a,mdxType:"MDXLayout"}),(0,r.yg)("p",null,"Here are 30 example questions for the Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark certification exam, along with their answers:"),(0,r.yg)("ol",null,(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is Apache Spark's primary abstraction for working with structured data?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," DataFrame")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which programming languages are officially supported by Apache Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Scala, Python, Java, and R")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the fundamental unit of data in Spark, represented as an immutable distributed collection of objects?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Resilient Distributed Dataset (RDD)")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark component is responsible for managing the execution of tasks in a parallel and fault-tolerant manner?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Spark Core")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which operation in Spark allows you to transform an RDD into another RDD by applying a function to each element?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"map"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation operation in Spark returns a new RDD containing only the elements that satisfy a given condition?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"filter"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"groupBy")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It groups elements in an RDD based on a key and applies a function to each group.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark transformation allows you to perform an aggregation across all elements of an RDD?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"reduce"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the primary advantage of using DataFrames over RDDs in Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," DataFrames offer better optimization and execution performance due to their schema information.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark operation is used to join two DataFrames based on a common column?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"join"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," In Spark, what is the purpose of a broadcast variable?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It allows you to efficiently distribute a read-only value to worker nodes.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which operation in Spark returns the first element of an RDD?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"first"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation in Spark flattens a nested structure by turning it into a flat list?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"flatMap"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the Spark SQL API used for?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It provides a way to work with structured data using SQL queries or DataFrame operations.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark transformation is used to sample data from an RDD?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"sample"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"distinct")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It returns a new RDD containing distinct elements of the original RDD.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:"),' In Spark, what does "lazy evaluation" mean?'),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Transformations on RDDs are not executed immediately but only when an action is called.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark action returns the number of elements in an RDD?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"count"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the difference between ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"cache")," and ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"persist")," operations in Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Both store RDD in memory, but ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"persist")," allows you to specify storage level.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which action in Spark returns a new RDD containing all elements of the source RDD in random order?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"repartition"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"union")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It combines two RDDs to create a new RDD containing all elements from both RDDs.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation in Spark returns a new RDD by applying a function to each partition?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"mapPartitions"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What does the ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"collect")," action in Spark do?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It retrieves all elements of an RDD and brings them to the driver program.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," In Spark, what is the purpose of the ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"take")," action?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It returns the first n elements of an RDD as an array.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation operation in Spark groups elements of an RDD by key and applies an aggregation function?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"reduceByKey"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the main advantage of using DataFrames over RDDs for structured data processing?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," DataFrames allow Spark to optimize query execution and offer better performance.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the key difference between a transformation and an action in Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Transformations create a new RDD from an existing one, while actions return a value or write data.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which action in Spark returns a new RDD containing a specified number of elements from the beginning?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"take"))),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"sortBy")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It sorts the elements of an RDD based on a key.")),(0,r.yg)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark transformation operation is used to filter an RDD by applying a function to each element?"),(0,r.yg)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.yg)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.yg)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"filter")))))}y.isMDXComponent=!0}}]);